Privacy Policy
==============

Polar Bears International (PBI) respects your privacy. We do not trade, share, nor sell your personal information with anyone, nor do we send donor mailings or other mailings on behalf of other organizations.

### Polar Bears International Donations and Adoptions

Polar Bears International collects names, street addresses, contact email addresses, telephone numbers, and credit card information when you make a donation or adopt a polar bear. We do not retain credit card information online. We keep a record of personal information derived from orders and donations to the extent required by our auditors to verify our accounting system.

If you adopt a polar bear, we may use your email or telephone number to request additional information about your order or preferred shipping method, or to notify you of your order status.

We may use your email address or mailing address to send you a free copy of our newsletter and/or information. If you don't want to receive communications from Polar Bears International, please let us know by marking that option on your personal contact information form, or by using the unsubscribe option on the information you receive.

### Membership

Polar Bears International retains names and email and mailing addresses—and all optional information you provide us—in our secure membership database, which we use to keep you informed of PBI business and issues. This information remains private within Polar Bears International.

### Log Files

Polar Bears International's website server maintains log files that contain IP addresses and/or domain names whenever you request a page. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information and we use information from the log files solely in the aggregate to analyze site traffic and evaluate public interest. The URL of a referring web page may also be logged for the same purpose.

### Cookies

The PBI website uses cookies only to send data between pages (state). The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifiable information. Click [here](#privacy-settings) to update your privacy settings.

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, which is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our website. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having your activity on the website made available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) for your web browser. The Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits and activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the [Google Privacy & Terms](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) web page.

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our customers and potential customers who visit. To assist us in this, we have implemented the Google Analytics Demographics and interest reporting features on our website. These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age, and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs. Although this information is collected through your Google Ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally identifiable format. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out. 

### Links

This website contains links to other websites. Polar Bears International is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites.

### Email

If you send Polar Bears International an email, your return address will be displayed in the header we receive. We will use this information only to answer your inquiry. We may on occasion keep your message as a record of the contact but at no time will we trade, share, or sell email information with others.

### Social Networks, Chat Windows, and Email Threads

Any identifying information you post in a social networking site, chat window, or an email will be public information. Polar Bears International will make no effort to collect personal information from these sources, but it's possible that other visitors may record your email address or other information. If this concerns you, please post under a pseudonym or with an altered email address.

### Age

Polar Bears International may ask you to voluntarily provide your birth date for certain communications programs we invite you to participate in (such as receiving an electronic birthday greeting). You are not required to provide this information unless you choose to participate.

### Polar Bears International Security

Polar Bears International provides our members and supporters with a secure experience when ordering memberships, making a donation, or adopting a polar bear. Any credit card information you enter on our site is strongly encrypted by industry-standard protocol, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer).

We take appropriate precautions to protect the security and privacy of the information stored on our computer networks. Our systems are secure, and access to your data by our employees is limited to a need to know basis, controlled by password-protected systems, and monitored for abuse.

### Reviewing Your Information

You may contact us at any time to review personal information collected and request revisions. Please direct any questions or comments to us at [privacy@pbears.org](mailto:privacy@pbears.org). You can also write to us at:

**Polar Bears International**  
PO Box 3008,  
Bozeman, MT  
59772

Photo: [Daniel J. Cox](https://naturalexposures.com/)

Join this conservation journey.
-------------------------------

Become part of a community committed to protecting polar bears with our free e-news.

Sign Up Now

**

**

**

**

**

**

**

**

**

**

Polar Bears & the Changing Arctic

What We Do

Education Center

Privacy Policy

News & Media

© 2024 Polar Bears International

Help ensure the polar bear's future.
------------------------------------

The actions we take today give polar bears a chance at an even better tomorrow.
